all right module seven revolving around which platforms you should choose when you're just
starting out pretty much the answer is free easy to use easy for you to use as well as easy for
your customers to use right go well this is going to be more revolving around where your customers
live and by live i don't mean like address i mean like are they scrolling through instagram all
the time are they reading the new york times are they uh on reddit subreddits where are they right
this is important if they're talking about this product should exist or you know if you don't
know reddit they have subreddits and they go by r slash so r slash skincare if you're selling
skin products that's where your demand might exist right you don't necessarily have to sell there
right that's a little over doing it but understand them at the very least and why they're there
optimize for access not reach you're not looking for um i'm going to be on instagram tiktok youtube
uh youtube shorts x uh reels right all of those things you're not necessarily looking for that
at the forefront you're looking for i'm going to message this person right where they are right
right where their problem or right where you see the problem so you also want to gauge this speed to
revenue if you're wasting or taking your time to build up as much content as possible on multiple
platforms it might take a while for you to get your first customer it'll definitely be a lot nicer
it's important to do but it's not the quickest way to your first sale or sales in general right
building out content is a more long-term journey for your business and you're going to realize that
soon enough it is an important metric 100 we'll go into it later but for this exercise it is not the
fastest way to get your first dollar this is going to be talking about um buyers versus creators right
where do the buyers live do they live on instagram youtube tiktok maybe it doesn't necessarily mean that
they are going to buy right now right um and let's talk about what buy right now means
if you are in the market for uh let's talk about uh i am in need of a lawyer
if i'm building out content i might be interested in the lawyer talking about a case but it doesn't
mean i need a lawyer right now right they might live on google ads or linkedin or upwork or google maps
right i might type in i need a lawyer in san diego right uh i got in a car crash what next
you need to live there right that would be great your google profile should showcase and come up as
the most relevant search that is a great use case for uh buyer hubs and as well as they are ready to buy
right now right and this is more regarding local networks you definitely want buyer intent as your
highest metric of where you should exist where you're most visible
this is going to be free right these are all your freemiums this is going to be calendly right this is on your
sales call it didn't pan out for them to buy right on the call so i'm so happy that you learned more
about our business customer a i know that we only had 30 minutes today are you available thursday
here's the link to schedule it and put it on your calendar on the call send a calendar link right
it went really well after maybe the second call let's just go with reality here let's go with the
second call and they are ready to buy and you're fumbling through a venmo request i don't know um
you've lost all of that trust that you've built on the two sales calls send them a stripe link
right again free to set up documents to this day we still use google drive google sheets
it is easily shareable customers understand it it's a link for them to access you can ensure only certain
people have access easy to use for both the business and the customers right you don't really want to
get too complex with this stuff um crm if you don't know what that means it just is a way for you to
track your customer journey uh customer relationship management this is name address phone number email
uh the status of where they are in the sales journey maybe they bought one product two products and you
want to upsell them three weeks down the line you are tracking that level of granularity for your customers
you should be doing this you might not be doing this on your uh first sale journey but you should have
some version of this right customer a spent x amount um it's been three months and maybe i want to call
them up and say hey how's it going um you you bought it uh all these three things how's it going and i want
to upsell them you should know that track it have notifications for this type of stuff um that way you
can zoom out of your business after the fact and understand your customers even more granularly
for now just use google sheets simple you don't need uh hub spots you don't need um notion just
make it simple
here's some more examples of where you can use free platforms right screenshot this whatever
um you don't need to make the perfect choice here again the tell all for what you should be using
should be on those sales calls when you fumble around with something you'll start to understand oh
uh if i had the payment link ready now if i had the invoice ready to go they might have bought right then
um answer these questions take this as a worksheet for your homework so you can further understand that
customer journey and i think in another course we're going to talk more about what that customer
journey looks like for both the business and your customer and it's another underrated skill set
that both service and product uh based businesses do not take advantage of sometimes you get stuck
i need to be the perfect lawyer so i can get more clients i need to have the perfect uh pair of
sunglasses so i can get more customers you're right but it is much more important especially at the
forefront to understand your customers first what do they really want if you have the most perfect
uh phone in the world and no customers know about it no customers think of it as a problem that exists
it is hard to change from one phone to the other right you need to know your customers you built the
perfect phone now what people are just going to flock who knows right
um and then here's your key takeaways all right on to the next module